(Sincro: bamanzi)
Oh, there's nothing like a dip to freshen you up.
噢, 没有什么比浸泡一下更能令人神清气爽了
Hey, that's a funny looking boat.
嘿, 那艘小船样子可真有意思
It's not a boat, it's a hovercraft.
那不是小船, 那是一艘气垫船
Eh?
嗯？
You're right, it is him.
你是对的, 就是他
What are we going to do?
我们要怎么做？
A terrifying thing. It's like a sea monster.
太可怕了, 就像一个海妖一样
Oh, we'll soon get a closer look, it's coming nearer.
哦, 很快我们就可以看清楚了, 它越来越近了
Oh yes. Yes.
哦, 对了, 对
I don't think I like the look of this. Let's go.
我觉得我不喜欢这事的样子, 走吧
- Why, what's the matter?  - Come on, run!
- 为啥, 什么情况？ - 快点, 跑！
- Yeah, but...  - Don't argue, run.
- 好吧, 但是...  - 别说了, 跑
Over here!
这边来！
Hurry!
快啊！
Incredible.
不可思议
Absolutely incredible.
绝对不可思议
I'm not a specimen in a glass bowl, you know?
我可不是玻璃缸里面的标本, 知道吗？
Ah, I'm sorry. Do sit down.
啊, 抱歉．请坐下
Oh, thank you.
噢, 谢谢你
It's just so astonishing. You are Salamander.
这太令人震惊了, 你是 Salamander
Do you see what I mean?
你明白我的意思吗？
But surely you know how alike you are?
但你肯定知道你长得多像吧？
After all, Salamander is a world figure.
毕竟来说, Salamander 是个世界级人物
Well... well my friends and I, we..
哦...我的朋友们和我，我们
we've been out of touch...
with civilisation for a while.
我们跟文明世界有段时间没有联系了
We're visitors, so to speak, um.
On ice shall we say.
我们是游客, 应该说, 唔, 应该说是与世隔绝了(?)
I see. Where shall I start?
我明白了．我应该从哪里开始呢？
At the beginning please.
We've been subjected to a number of attacks
请从一开始讲起．我们已经遭受了一系列的攻击了
because I look like this Salamander of yours.
仅仅因为我看起来像你们的这个 Salamander
I'm not surprised. I'll show you why.
我不感到奇怪, 我会让你看看为什么
I have a video wire of Salamander,
我这里有段 Salamander 的视频
addressing the United Zones Conference on World Food.
他在联合区域大会的世界粮食专题的讲话
And meanwhile, over at the United Zones General Assembly,
from all over the world delegates are flocking in,
与此同时, 在联合区域大会上, 代表们从世界各地涌来
eager to hear the latest report from Leader Salamander.
都急切地想听到 Salamander 组长的最新报告
The progress, Mr President, of the Sun Conservation
establishment at Kanowa, in the Australasian Zone is...
总统先生, 对于建立在澳洲区 Kanowa 的日光保留区的进展 ...
...I'm delighted to report highly satisfactory.
...我很高兴地报告给大家：高度满意
But we cannot yet guarantee good summer holidays for all.
但我们无法保障所有地方都有漂亮的夏日
However, we have now in orbit the Mark VII Sun Catcher...
然而, 现在我们的轨道上也有了日光采集器７号
and already we have been able to
concentrate the sun's rays into much needed areas.
而且我们也已经能够将太阳射线聚焦到更有需要的区域
The great Canadian wheat plains are safe.
泛加拿大片区的小麦植物很安全
And now, Mr President: Ukraine - the grain field of the planet -
现在, 总统先生, 乌克兰 - 这个星球最主要的谷物种植地
an unfortunate area between Bucava and Kirovograd
介于 Bucava 和 Kirovograd 之间的一片不幸区域
devastated by the elements two short years ago.
两年前被自然灾害严重破坏
What have I got to say to you about that?
对此我有什么可以跟你说的呢？
I can tell you that on both banks of the Dnieper river
the corn is ripening in the sun!
我可以告诉你在第聂伯河的两岸，玉米正在阳光下成熟！
And ten-thousand robot harvesters are moving down
to gather in fifty million tons of flour!
一万台机械收割机已经出发, 去收割五千万顿面粉！
There's nothing there to say he's a bad man.
真没法说他是一个坏人
I quite agree, Victoria.
He seems to be a public benefactor.
我相当赞成, Victoria. 他似乎是一个为大众利益着想的人
Quite a speaker too and remarkably handsome,
didn't you think so Jamie?
相当会说话, 也极其有魅力．你不觉得吗, Jamie?
He's one of the most popular men on the planet.
他是这个星球上最受欢迎的人之一
Many people call him the shopkeeper of the world.
很多人称呼他为这个世界的掌柜(?)
The saviour, in fact, some of them.
救世主, 事实上有些人这样称呼他
Well what's he saved the world from?
哦, 他把这个世界从什么手里救了？
Starvation - too many people, too little food.
饥荒 - 人太多, 食物太少
Until Salamander invented his Sun Store.
Surely you've heard? You must know?
直到 Salamander 发明了日光储存器．你肯定听说过吧？
Oh yes, well of course we've heard something.
噢, 是的, 当然了我们听说了一点
The Sun Store collects the rays from the sun
and stores them in concentrated form.
日光存储器采集太阳射线, 集中存储起来
Oh, like the ioniser, Doctor?
喔, 就像离子器吧, 博士？
Yes, a rather different principle I think, Jamie.
是的, 但原理上很不一样, 据我了解, Jamie
Well never mind how it works! What's it for?
得了别管它什么原理了！它是用来干什么的？
Salamander can force-grow three,
sometimes four, crops in one summer.
Salamander 可以强制让作物在一个夏天就长三茬, 甚至四茬
Well why do these men want to kill him.
那为什么这些人还想杀他
I mean, one minute you say he's saving the world, the next...
我是说, 前一分钟你说他拯救了世界, 下一分钟...
For his own ends! Step by step
he's taking control of this planet.
他有他自己的目的！一步一步地, 他掌握了这个星球的控制权
You have proof of this?
你说这个有证据吗？
Some, yes. I was once a high official
in the World Zone Authority
是的, 有一些．我一度也是世界区域总部的一名高官
Deputy Security Leader for North Africa and Europe,
but Salamander discredited and ruined me
是北非和欧洲的安全副主管. 但 Salamander 抹黑了我, 让我下台
because he realized I was beginning to get suspicious.
因为他发现我开始起疑了
But you could be making up stories about Salamander!
Out of revenge.
但你可能是在编造 Salamander 的故事, 出于报复！
Yes, I suppose so. Then you can judge for yourself.
是的, 我也会这么想. 你可以自己判断
You remember Michael Assevski -
he was Controller of the Eastern European Zone?
你记得 Michael Assevski 吗？曾经的西欧区控制员？
He was drowned at sea a mile from shore.
(s/Shockingly/Hockingham,/) murdered!
他在离海岸一英里的地方淹死了. 可怕的谋杀啊!
All of them were seen with Salamander,
or a man known as his deputy
所有这些人都被见到跟 Salamander 在一起, 或者他的副官
shortly before their deaths.
都是在他们死前不久
All of them were replaced by men
known to be in Salamander's power.
据了解，所有这些人都被 Salamander 的人取而代之
- Known by who?   - By me, Doctor.
- 据谁了解？  - 我, 博士
Well why don't you tell the authorities,
the police or whatever?
那, 你怎么不告诉当局, 警察什么的？
Because I'm discredited, don't you see?
因为我名誉扫地了, 你没明白吗？
Because Salamander is so popular,
由于 Salamander 是如此受欢迎
and also because the man that took my place,
a man named Donald Bruce...
也因为那个顶了我位置的人, Donald Bruce...
...has since risen to become overall security chief.
...已经升到了安全总管的位置
Surely there is someone you can take your story to?
肯定你还有些人可以把故事讲给他们听？
Ah yes, Helvig believed me.
So did Assevski, and they're dead.
啊是有, Helvig 信我, Assevski 也是, 而他们都死了
However, there is one other man,
a man named Alexander Denes,
不过, 还有一个人, 名字叫做 Alexander Denes
but none of them will do anything until it's too late!
但他们没一个打算做点什么, 眼看着一切变得太迟！
I'm surprised.
我觉得奇怪
Well if Salamander is everything you say he is,
then why hasn't he tried to...
如果 Salamander 完全是你说的这种人, 那他怎么没有试图...
- Dispose of me?  - Yes
- 干掉我？  - 对
Well he has, but he's afraid.
他试过, 但他害怕
You see, the testimony of a dead man
still holds legal weight.
你知道, 一个死人的证词还是有法律效应的
Oh, I see. Well, it seems we have a problem on our hands...
哦, 我明白了．那, 看来我们手头有一个问题是...
...whether to believe Mr Kent or not.
...要信任 Kent 先生还是不要
Well there is one way that you can find out for yourselves.
那好．这里有一个方法, 你们可以自己弄清楚真相
Oh, how?
噢, 什么方法？
Impersonate Salamander.
假冒 Salamander
Yes I thought that's what we were leading up to.
是啊, 我估计我们就要被往这条路上引
Well I must admit, Doctor, you do look like him.
是, 我必须承认, 博士, 你真的很像他
Exactly like him.
非常像他
Yes, there's more to it than that. What about the voice?
是, 但还有别的方面, 比如说嗓音怎么办？
Well it's nearly the same pitch, only the accent.
调门差不多, 只是口音问题
Only the accent! My dear young lady.
只是口音问题！我亲爱的年轻女士
Oh dear. Now what was it he said...
噢, 天啊。他说了什么来着
We still cannot guarantee good summer holidays for all.
"但我们无法保障所有地方都有漂亮的夏日"
No. Guarantee... no, no, no... guaran... guarantee.
You see, it's very difficult.
不对. "保障..." 不不不, "保...保障"．你看, 这非常困难
Hmm, of course I always was interested in phonetics
嗯, 当然了我一直对发音有兴趣
Holidays... summer... summer.
＂假日...夏天..夏天＂
He must have come from Mexico,
Quintana Roo or Yucatan or somewhere...
他肯定是来自墨西哥, Quintana Roo 州或者 Yucatan 州什么的
That's incredible, Doctor, he was born at Merida,
state capital of Yucatan.
神啊, 博士．他出生在 Merida, 是 Yucantan 州的省会
Yes, there are other very strong influences though.
是了, 但还受到了一些其它地方的强印象
Oh, I could do it in time.
But what if I did it, what then?
噢, 我可以及时搞定．但如果我搞定了, 然后怎样？
You could walk into Salamander's research station at Kanowa,
你可以进入 Salamander 在 Kanowa 的研究站
find out how he's getting control of the separate
World Zones, and then bring out absolute proof.
发现他是如何操纵世界各区的, 把切实的证据带出来
Yes. I see.
好, 我明白了
How long did you say it would take you
to master Salamander's accent?
你说你掌握 Salamander 的口音需要多久？
I didn't. It would take three weeks, perhaps four.
我没说过．需要三个星期, 或者四个
Well while we've been talking,
the Security Chief I told you about,
但是我们说话的这会儿, 我跟你说过的安全总管...
Donald Bruce, has since cordoned off this entire area.
...Donald Bruce, 已经封锁了这整个区域
He's coming here himself...Now!
他自己会过来... 就现在！
I'd say you've got about two minutes, Doctor.
我得说你只有大约两分钟, 博士
But that's out of the question!
但这根本不可能啊！
You know what he'll do as soon as he sees you,/?
你知道他一看见你就会做什么吗
a man who resembles Salamander so closely?
你跟 Salamander 如此之像？
- Oh that's not fair!
- Will you please listen!
- 噢, 真不公平！  - 你肯听我说一句吗！
You'll be under arrest for impersonation
as soon as he sees you. I mean it.
他一看见你, 你就会因冒充而被逮捕的．我说真的
But isn't there another way out of this?
但就没有别的办法了吗？
Only one - be Salamander.
只有一个 - 成为 Salamander
But the clothes!
但是衣服呢！
Yes, there are some in here.
A little less eccentric, but do the best you can.
有, 这里有一些．表现自然一点, 但要尽力而为
I won't! I can't!
我不能！我做不到！
Your friends, Doctor, do you want them to suffer?
你的朋友们, 博士, 你想他们受罪吗？
Because they will, you know.
他们会的, 你知道
No, wait a minute! Why is a man like Bruce coming here?
不, 等一下？为什么 Bruce 这样的人会到这里来？
Don't push me, there isn't time.
别推我, 没有时间了
You sent for him, didn't you? You tipped him off!
你叫他来的, 是不是？你透露消息给他了！
I couldn't miss an opportunity like this,
now please come on.
我不可能错失这样的机会．现在请快点吧
Giles, for heaven's sake, what have you done?
It's far too risky.
Giles, 老天在上, 你做什么了？这风险太大了
Hello Kent. Doing some recruiting are you?
你好 Kent．在招募人吗？
A bit young for killers, aren't they?
他们做杀手有点年轻了吧, 是不是？
What do you mean?
你什么意思？
All right, what do you mean by stepping in here like this?
好了, 你这样闯进来是什么意思？
Anytime, Kent. I've got the right and you know it.
Anytime I like.
随时, Kent．我有这个权力, 你知道的．我爱什么时候都行
All right, what do you want?
好吧, 你想要什么？
That's better, you're ex-security,
you know the way it's got to go.
这好多了。你是前任安全官, 你知道接下来会怎样
We might as well be nice and civil about it, mightn't we?
我们还是同样会礼貌而文明的, 对吧？
That bungalow in Cedar District. In your name, right?
Cedar 区的小平房, 是你名下的, 对吧
Why?
为什么？
Do I have to tell you?
There's been an awful nasty mess out there.
非得我告诉你吗？那里可真是血腥混乱啊
Someone has got himself shot in your living room.
有个人在你的起居室自杀了
- And who are you two?  - Jamie McCrimmon
- 你俩是谁？  - Jamie McCrimmon
- And?  - Victoria Waterfield
- 还有？  - Victoria Waterfield
- What's the matter, can't you speak?
- Don't shout at me.
- 什么情况, 你不会说话吗？  - 别朝我喊
Oh, very good, the outraged public citizen.
噢, 很好, 愤怒的公民
- Do they know who I am?
- Yes they do.
- 他们知道我是谁吗？  - 是的他们知道
A pity, I like to hear you say it.
可惜．我想听你说一遍
Now listen to this, all of you.
现在听着, 你们所有人
One of your men was murdered in a bungalow rented to you.
有一个你的人被谋杀了，就在租给你的房子里
The remains of two others were found
in what was left of a helicopter.
另外两个人的尸体在一辆直升机里面发现了
You were in that bungalow at the time.
当时你在那个平房里
And there were three other people with you,
two youngsters and a man. Right?
当时有三个人跟你在一起．两个小年青和一个中年人, 对吧
Now, there was another man, wasn't there?
好, 之前还有一个人, 是不是？
So we'll deal with that first? Where is he?
所以我们先来说说那个。他在哪儿？
Why hello Bruce, what are you doing here, huh?
哟, 你好 Bruch, 你在这里做什么, 哈?